Pro-Brush Image Collection
Pro-Brush Image Collection
1970s
Warner-Lambert Company.
1 linear ft.
Contains 1406 slides of machinery and plastic products of the Pro-Brush company, and 45 color transparencies and 20 fading Polaroid snapshots of models posing with Pro-Brush products.
2651150
Biographical History
The A. P Critchlow Company in Florence, Massachusetts, which made buttons, daguerreotype cases and picture frames, evolved into the Florence Manufacturing Company by 1866. Their premier product, the Pro-phy-lactic toothbrush, occasioned a change in name to the Prophylactic Brush Company. In 1931, it was bought out by the Lambert Company. The Lambert Company merged with Warner-Hudnite Company in 1932 to become Warner-Lambert Prophylactic Division of Standard Oil of Ohio. The abbreviation of "Pro-Brush" was adopted.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Pro-Brush Image Collection contains 1406 slides of machinery and plastic products of the Pro-Brush company, and 45 color transparencies and 20 fading Polaroid snapshots of models posing with Pro-Brush products.
Related Material
has numerous holdings in the areas of plastics and industrial design. Please refer to for a complete listing.
Subject and Genre Headings
Business and Industry; Plastics; Prophylactic Brush Company.; Warner-Lambert Company -- Archives.; Plastics industry and trade.; Plastics machinery.; Toothbrushes.; Photographs.; Promotional materials.; Slides (photographs); Transparencies.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Transfer from National Plastics Center and Museum, 11/06/2008.
Inventory
- Slides
  - Manufacturing, ca. 1970s (Box 1)
  - Models, ca. 1970s (Box 1)
  - People, ca. 1970s (Box 1)
  - Plants and buildings, ca. 1970s (Box 1)
  - Products and objects, ca. 1970s (Box 1)
  - Products and objects, ca. 1970s (Box 2)
  - Text and diagrams, ca. 1970s (Box 1)
- Photographs
  - Polaroids, 1970s; models posing with Pro-Brush products (Box 2)
  - Transparencies, 1970s; models posing with Pro-Brush products; transparencies have turned to the reddened stage of deterioration and Polaroids have deteriorated dramatically (Box 2)
- Printed material
  - Florence Manufacturing, "Pro-phy-lactic Brush" ad, circa 1910-1924 (Map-case 1, Drawer 97)